liveinmelbourne.vic.gov.au 2019-03-04

# Privacy - Live in Melbourne

As part of the Victorian Government’s Department of Jobs, Precincts and Regions (DJPR), the Skilled and Business Migration Program values the privacy of every individual's personal information and health information.

We are committed to protecting the information we collect and use by complying with the Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 and the Health Records Act 2001.

Protecting your privacy and your personal and health information is an important aspect of the way we create, organise and implement our activities online and offline.

You can access our website home page and browse our site without disclosing personal information. We will only record an individual's email address and/or contact details if they send our site a message. The information an individual provides is collected for the purposes of responding to the matters raised in an individual’s electronic correspondence.

We will only collect personal information that is necessary to perform these functions. We will only use personal information provided for the purposes for which it was collected.

We will ensure that your personal information will not be disclosed to other institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation.

When you provide us with personal information about other individuals, we rely on you to make them aware that such information will or may be provided to us, the types of third parties we may provide it to, the relevant purposes that we and such third parties will use it for, and how they can access it.

We have implemented technology and security policies, rules and measures to protect the personal information that we have under our control from unauthorised access, improper use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss.

We will remove personal information where it is no longer required (except where archiving is required and in compliance with the Public Records Act 1973). We will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is accurate, complete and up to date whenever we collect, disclose or use it.

**Please note:**  
This privacy statement does not extend beyond this website. When clicking on links to other sites from this website, we recommend that you read the privacy statement of that site to familiarise yourself with its privacy principles.

## Privacy statement for Skilled and Business Migration

This policy explains how the Skilled and Business Migration Program collects, uses and discloses personal information, including through our websites. The Skilled and Business Migration Program is bound by and adopts the Information Privacy Principles set out in Schedule 1 of the Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Vic) ("Act"). The Skilled and Business Migration Program views the protection of personal information as an important issue and is committed to the protection and responsible handling of personal information it collects.

This Privacy Statement may change from time to time.

### Your personal information

Personal information is information about you, whether recorded in a material form or not, from which your identity could reasonably be ascertained. The types of personal information we may collect includes name, gender, address, telephone numbers, email contact details, occupational details, certain details about your personal qualifications and other information relevant to the business activities undertaken by the Skilled and Business Migration Program from time to time.

Where the Skilled and Business Migration Program requests that you provide your personal information and you elect not to provide it, the Skilled and Business Migration Program may not be able to provide you with some or all of its services.

### Collection of personal information

The Skilled and Business Migration Program collects personal information from a variety of sources, including:

  * communications between you and the Skilled and Business Migration Program, including via email, telephone or in writing (for example, surveys, feedback forms, visa application forms, registration for events, competitions and promotions, online enquiries);
  * your participation in discussions and interviews with the Skilled and Business Migration Program and promotions or competitions organised by the Skilled and Business Migration Program;
  * when you access or register on the Live in Melbourne website; and
  * from publicly available sources of information.

Information is collected, wherever possible, from you directly. The Skilled and Business Migration Program will collect your personal information lawfully, fairly and without undue intrusion. At the time your personal information is collected, the Skilled and Business Migration Program will take reasonable steps to advise you whether there are any consequences of not providing that information. The Skilled and Business Migration Program will not collect sensitive personal information about you unless the Skilled and Business Migration Program first obtains your consent through your agreement e.g. the Skilled and Business Visa Application Declaration Form before submitting a visa application on the Live in Melbourne website.

### Use and disclosure of personal information

The personal information you provide to the Skilled and Business Migration Program gives valuable insights into skilled and business migration. This information can, in turn, help the Skilled and Business Migration Program to achieve its goals of finding and communicating new and effective ways to connect with prospective skilled and business migrants. To do this, the Skilled and Business Migration Program may use your personal information for a variety of purposes, including research and analysis. The Skilled and Business Migration Program may also send you information and updates about the Skilled and Business Migration Program's initiatives, events and services and provide you with information, news and updates relating to migration. If you do not wish to receive these updates or information, please [contact us](https://liveinmelbourne.vic.gov.au/contact-us).

The Skilled and Business Migration Program also uses personal information for the purpose(s) that are communicated to you at the time of collection (or a related purpose that you would reasonably expect).

The Skilled and Business Migration Program may disclose your personal information to third parties, such as:

  * web monitoring service providers;
  * other government and regulatory authorities and other organisations (as required or authorised by law or as is reasonably necessary for the assistance for law enforcement and the protection of public revenue);
  * its profession advisors (such as auditors);
  * organisations that assist the Skilled and Business Migration Program to conduct research or analyse data;
  * other organisations that assist the Skilled and Business Migration Program to provide services to you from time to time.

We take reasonable steps to ensure these third parties are bound by confidentiality and privacy obligations in relation to the protection of your personal information.

### Data quality and security

The Skilled and Business Migration Program will take reasonable steps to:

  * ensure that the personal information it collects, uses or discloses is accurate, complete and up-to-date (however, the accuracy of your information depends on the information you provide and whether you keep the Skilled and Business Migration Program updated on changes); and
  * protect your personal information from misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure and securely destroy personal information if it is no required for any purpose.

The Skilled and Business Migration Program has implemented technology and security policies, rules and measures to help protect the personal information that is under its control. However, while the Skilled and Business Migration Program strives to protect your personal information, the Skilled and Business Migration Program cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to it online.

### Access

You have a right to access your personal information. In accordance with the Act, requests for access should be made via formal application under the Freedom of Information Act 1982 (Vic) (though in certain circumstances requests may be dealt with by the Skilled and Business Migration Program without the need to make formal application). Requests for access should be sent to the Department of Jobs, Precincts and Regions using the information in the Privacy Officer Contact Details section below.

### Anonymity

Wherever it is practicable and lawful, the Skilled and Business Migration Program will allow you to interact anonymously with us.

### Website privacy

You can visit and browse the Live in Melbourne website without disclosing your personal information. However, where you submit you personal information on a website (e.g. complete and submit a web form), your personal information will be managed in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

The Live in Melbourne website contains links to various other third party sites. The Skilled and Business Migration Program is not responsible for the content and the privacy practices of other websites and does not endorse or authorise the content of any third party websites. The Skilled and Business Migration Program encourages you to examine each site's privacy policy and make your own decisions about providing personal information whilst visiting those sites.

The Skilled and Business Migration Program uses a variety of web monitoring technologies (via third party service providers) to gather information to assist in improving the sites and making them more user-friendly. These technologies include:

  * Google Analytics and Yandex.Metrica web analytics: This data refers to visitor logs and statistics about the path a user takes while using a site. This technology is used purely for statistical purposes (such as tracking unique browsers to the sites); and
  * Cookies: Cookies are small data files that are placed on a user's hard drive, which are used to collect statistical information each time a user accesses a site (for example, the number of visits to the website, documents viewed, how the site is navigated and the type of search engine used to arrive at the site).

You may be able to disable or avoid some of these technologies by adjusting your Internet browser settings, though doing so may prevent you from taking advantage of improvements to the sites. Importantly, at no time can individual users be identified from the data collected via these means.

## Application of this privacy statement for DJPR

This privacy statement applies only to the Department and this particular website. It is consistent with the Department’s privacy policy and applies to all activities of the Department and its agencies.

This website contains links to other websites. This privacy statement does not apply to those websites.

The Department’s privacy policy is available from the Privacy Officer.

### Privacy officer contact details

Department of Department of Jobs, Precincts and Regions

GPO Box 4509

Melbourne, VIC, 3001, AUS

**Tel:** (+61 3) 8392 6329

**Email:** [privacy@djpr.vic.gov.au](mailto:privacy@djpr.vic.gov.au)

## Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Vic): Personal information

In this privacy statement the term 'personal information' has the meaning provided in section 3 of the _Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014_ (Vic).

Personal information is information or an opinion that is recorded in any form, whether true or not, about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained.

This Act is the legislation that regulates our collection and handling of personal information.

Detailed information about the Act is available at the [Office of the Commissioner for Privacy and Data Protection](http://www.cpdp.vic.gov.au/)

### Collection of personal information

It is intended that this website can be used anonymously. However, for some functions, the collection of personal information is necessary or unavoidable. You will know if the Department is collecting personal information from you because you will be requested to provide it.

There are two exceptions to this:

  * When someone else provides the Department with your personal information. The Department cannot prevent this. However, you are entitled to access and to correct any personal information about you collected by the Department
  * When the Department collects website visitation statistics using a web analytics service. For further information regarding this, see the Website Usage Measurement section.

The statistics collected from website visitation may qualify as personal information under the _Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014_ (Vic.). However, these statistics are not used to identify individual web users.

### Use and disclosure of personal information

If you provide personal information, the Department’s privacy policy will regulate its use and disclosure. However, should the department’s intended use and disclosure of personal information deviate from the Department’s general policy, a privacy statement particular to the circumstances will be made available at the time of collection.

Personal information that is collected by the Department will be used by, and disclosed to, Departmental employees or contractors whose duties require them to use it. Such employees and contractors are required to protect and handle your personal information in accordance with the _Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014_ (Vic.) and any other applicable legislation regulating the collection, use, disclosure, storage and destruction of personal information.

### Access to and correction of personal information

You may request access to any personal information that the department may have collected about you. Also, you may request correction of your personal information if you can establish that it is not accurate, complete or up-to-date. The Victorian Privacy Commissioner has recommended that the appropriate means to access and correct information held by government departments is pursuant to the _Freedom of Information Act 1982_ (Vic.).

Contact the Freedom of Information Officer about access to, and correction of, personal information collected by the department or for any questions or concerns you may have arising from this privacy statement:

**Freedom of Information Officer**

Department of Department of Jobs, Precincts and Regions

GPO Box 2392

Melbourne, VIC, 3001, AUS

**Tel:** (+61 3) 9208 3112

**Email:** [foi@djpr.vic.gov.au](mailto:foi@djpr.vic.gov.au)

## Internet user risks

The Department does not warrant that the functions contained in the site will be uninterrupted or without error. In addition, the Department shall not be responsible for the propagation of computer worms, viruses or other harmful components transmitted from this site and other third-party sites.

The Department recommends that you ensure that your browser is equipped with updated virus protection software.

### Website usage measurement

This website uses Google Analytics and Yandex. Metrica web analytics. These web analytics products use "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the us analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by these three companies on servers in various locations throughout the world, including the United States of America. These three companies will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. These three companies may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on the three companies' behalf. The three companies will not associate your IP address with any other data held by themselves.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by these three companies in the manner and for the purposes set out in this Web Usage Measurement section.

For further information, please visit the [Google Privacy Center](http://www.google.com/privacy.html "External link \(will open in new window\)") and the [Yandex.Metrica Terms of Use](http://legal.yandex.com/metrica_termsofuse/).

### Email addresses

Email addresses will only be used to respond to specific user queries and will not be kept or used for any purpose other than stated. Email addresses will not be added to a mailing list unless consent is given, nor disclosed to any other party without your knowledge or consent.

### Cookies

This site uses 'cookies' to make your experience of the site easier and more efficient. A cookie is a small data file placed on your hard drive by the web page server. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive, pass on a computer virus, or capture your email address. Note that the cookie will remain on your computer as a record for future visits to this website.

In using cookies the Department does not record any personal information or collect names or details of commercial transactions. In addition, the Department does not use cookies as the basis for direct marketing.

You can configure your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, providing you with the opportunity to either accept or reject it. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser or deleting all cookies from your computer if required.
